And this is where I'm a Bitcoin maxi in
the very long term. Woo! No, no, no. I
believe if you want to, let's let me
rephrase it. I want an asset that will
be growing in value for the next 30
years. The only one I can say in my
brain with certainty for the next 30
years, not the next five, not the next
three, that I believe is Bitcoin. That's
it. All right, guys. Today we have an
excellent conversation with Jordy
Visser. In this one, we go through
what's going on in AI. Why all of a
sudden when interest rates were raised,
why did Bitcoin, stocks, all this stuff
not crash? what is going on in the US
economy? Why does Jordy think that
Bitcoin's going higher? Other cryptos
are going higher. How does he think
about all of the agent swarms and issues
that are coming out of the AI industry?
And then Jordy just gives it to us
straight exactly where he thinks value
is going to acrue over the next couple
of years. What he's excited about, what
he's not excited about, and how it could
impact your portfolio. This one is
excellent. Here's my latest conversation
with Jordy Visser. All right, Jordy.
Bitcoin has held pretty steady.
Actually, it's up a little bit since the
Fed decided to raise interest rates.
Stock market is well pretty much flat.
AI indexes, they're up. I think that
people are a little offsides or shaken
that if the Fed increases interest
rates, aren't these assets all supposed
to go down? What's going on here? I
think you can take it back further.
Let's say June 30th. What's happened
since June 30th? That was the end of Q2.
Stocks are unchanged, both NASDAQ and
S&P.
Oil's a lot higher. I don't know if
you've heard, but oil is going to take
down the world. Tenure rates, they're up
a lot. I don't know if you heard this.
They're up a lot. Whole systems going to
crack.
Situational awareness happened in July.
AI bubbles unwound. Everything's going
to crash. We're in a
1998. We're in a 2009, whatever you
want. We get out of July. And then what
happens? Besson's going to go intervene
in the yen. And then he's going to
change the buybacks. And then he's going
to do this. It's going to make rates go
down. Rates go higher. The war gets
worse. Oil goes higher. Fed's not going
to raise rates. The Fed raises rates.
Clarity Act is going to go through.
Clarity Act doesn't go through.
Not only is Bitcoin, Ethereum,
everything sitting up here. Ethereum's
up over 50% quarter to date. So, with
all the news I just said, climbing a
wall of worry is a big deal. Um, if you
ask me what's going on, it's very simple
to me. You got to go back to situational
awareness.
And everyone who's listening, he hates
when I do this. Pause. Just pause for a
second. Go to your smartphone and just
so give me the image on page 71 of
Leopold situational awareness 165page
paper and I want you to look at that
exact point and that's where
>> we'll just pull it up here so you don't
have to pause.
>> That's where
that's where agents take over, AI agents
take over. And I think what has happened
to crypto, plain and simple, is the
enthusiasm came from, oh, the basement's
coming. And I will keep saying it for
all of you people listening. You want
rates to go higher and crypto to go
higher because a true technology, a true
innovation means it is not sensitive to
that. This has been a big mistake that I
have strong disagreement with the entire
crypto community that Bitcoin is just
liquidity. No, Bitcoin has been
liquidity because there hasn't been
innovation that has been used. When you
get to the inflection point where
innovation starts to be used like with
the iPhone, then that growth and
innovation happens without the business
cycle, without liquidity. So, if you
truly to be what everyone believes it's
going to be, which I believe it is now,
you actually need the true users of
crypto to come into play. Now, if rates
are going up, which they did just this
week, and crypto is still going up,
people will say, "Okay, if Bitcoin was
sensitive to liquidity before, will it
be sensitive going forward?" And I asked
that because I don't know if you've seen
the chart, the M2 money supply is going
up and Bitcoin used to track very nicely
and there have been times where they
diverged and you get kind of the
alligator, you know, mouth, but then
when it closes, there's a violent move
in Bitcoin to catch up to M2. We have
been living through for the last, I
don't know, 18 months or so, that
divergence again. And so M2 has been
growing. Bitcoin has been down. And
there's a belief in the Bitcoin
community that those jaws are going to
close and Bitcoin is going to violently
move up. What I hear you saying is maybe
that was true in the past, but the
drivers of Bitcoin's price going forward
may be more reliant on AI agents and
other innovation more so than what's
going on in the macro world. Is that a
fair summarization?
>> So,
I'm spending a lot of time. So, one of
the reasons that I wanted to do this
with you is this moment in time. Um, the
four-year cycle to me is is reflective
of the liquidity cycle. Um, I was just
listening to someone who I respect talk
about the liquidity cycle. Um, the
liquidity
>> there could only be one guy who talks
about the liquidity cycle non-stop. Go.
>> Well, no, they were probably thinking of
the same person. It wasn't him, but it
was someone directly related to him. Um
here here here's the thing I'll say is
um in fact that person he and I spoke
one time and I said there's no such
thing as recessions anymore.
>> I agree with that.
>> Okay. So if you don't have recessions
anymore the liquidity cycle is not the
same. That doesn't mean that the
government doesn't try to prevent stock
market crashes and prevent possible
recessions that they're worried about.
So when you look at the liquidity cycle,
you have to remember what makes M2 go
down is when humans start getting
worried about things and they start
hoarding cash and they start putting it
into noneconomic places. They're paying
off debt or they're doing something, but
they're not actually generating GDP with
it. So there has been a link between
liquidity
forever
and M2 and then you get GDP and then you
know what happens after you get GDP? Hm.
>> Liquidity turns into more jobs.
We're not doing that anymore. Um it
turns into profits first and then it
goes into there. So we have the S&P 500
growing at 30% earnings and the hiring
ex healthcare is negative over the last
20 months. Think about that. We've had
no job creation over the last 20 months
except for healthcare
>> fraud. Go ahead. So we have no job
creation. How are we breaking it? So the
the percentage of capital verse labor is
now at at the worst in history for
labor. So we've broken the liquidity
mechanism. Now how is the stock market
growing so fast? Because liquidity leads
to nominal GDP. Nominal GDP is topline
revenue. Money transaction. People get
hired, they spend more money. How in
God's name do we actually have this
mechanism still working? And this is why
the liquidity cycle is not about Bitcoin
anymore. Liquidity cycle in 2009 began
with the efficiency of productivity.
finally entering up. So the internet was
born in 1994 in terms of when Netscape
went public. Then we had the.com bubble.
That was the version of crypto that
period into the dotcom bubble and after
where we were building the rails for
commerce. It didn't come until the
smartphone came. And when the smartphone
came, we had an explosion of
productivity that showed up in profit
margins. It did not show up in GDP, but
I've talked about that. It's a horrible
index for what we're dealing with with
software and intangibles. But what is
happening now is we've broken the
liquidity mechanism. So I will say it
again to everyone. We will be having
more liquidity in the system but not
through the liquidity measures that
people talk about. Tokenization
unleashes dormant assets $900 trillion
of assets of which twothirds just sit
and do nothing.
>> They will be used as collateral. They
will be in daily transactions. You won't
have to go to get a a a borrow money
from your bank. It'll be programmable
and stuff where you post something for a
period of time, waiting for your
receivables to come in and then it goes.
The whole system will be based on the
velocity of money. So remember liquidity
M2 is about the government putting money
into the system. We have plenty of money
to run the system not showing up in
profit margins and showing in topline
revenue.
>> Do you hear that right now?
>> From whom? Me? Yes.
>> No, no, no, no. Do you hear? If you open
your ear,
>> yeah,
>> it's everyone laughing at the Fed and
saying, "You thought you were going to
tank the stock market. You thought you
were going to slow us down. they're just
pouring money in even though rates went
up. And I think part of this is yes,
there is less rate sensitivity in some
of these names. But I also think that
there is a fullblown psychological
revolution that has occurred where run
the counter uh example or analysis. What
would have to happen for all of the
people who are talking about stocks on X
or on YouTube sit inside these firms to
actually stop buying? I don't think I
could think of a single thing that could
occur that could get them to stop buying
because probably the single worst thing
that could have happened happened in
2020. They locked everyone in their
houses. They stopped the velocity of
money and they basically froze the world
as best they could
and stocks ended the year higher than
they started.
>> So if you think of that, it just was
like we pulled back the curtain like
Wizard of Oz style and everyone's like,
"Wait a minute. No matter what happens,
if you keep buying stocks,
you're going to make money." And it
feels like that actually broke the
market almost more than anything else.
And that's why maybe interest rates like
all of this stuff like the innovation
thing is big
>> but the psychology piece feels like it
is a huge piece of it as well.
>> All right. So
rather than like
>> do you disagree?
>> No no no I agree. In fact I'm going to
I'm going to take it to a higher
extreme.
>> So in 2020 we shut down the economy.
>> Are you about to out crazy me? Well, I'm
about to take you through a timeline of
let's assume it's back at December 31st
of 2019.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We're going to shut the economy
for a period of time. Assets are going
to collapse significantly.
>> Um yields, credit yields for almost all
corporate credits, IG, are going to go
to double digits.
>> And yes, we end we end that year with
stocks higher somehow.
Everyone's worried about dying. Truly
dying. Not the AI is going to kill us
all, but truly we're watching people
die. We're watching the hospitals be
overrun. And yet the stock market's up.
>> Then we get to 2022.
We go from 0% rates to five aggressively
like never before and inflation is
double digits. The market that year is
down, but very quickly the following
year, despite the fact that in 2023, we
also have Silicon Valley Bank goes out
of business. M the largest bank that
goes from they're healthy to zero ever
and we start seeing money leave the
banking system. It's leaving all small
banks. We're getting many small bank
closures. We finish that year higher in
the year. Then we get a new president.
We go into 2025. We're going to go back
to Smoot Holly and we're going to put
tariffs on everything. Massive tariffs.
Everyone calls for another recession.
So let's take that period there.
There's no recession during all of those
events in especially the 2022 one where
we raised aggressively and everyone said
this is going to be a problem. This is
it. It was a guaranteed recession. The
Fed was saying sell your stocks.
>> Mhm.
>> Then you get to this year we shut down
the straight of Hormuz.
So, Smoot Holy, straight of horm, bank
runs, uh, a pandemic, and the most
aggressive Fed rate hikes in history, no
recessions. So, now we're going to worry
about a 25 basis point move by the Fed.
>> A raise for ants.
>> Yeah, that is discounted in the market
ahead of them doing it. Oh my god, they
raised rates. It was a hawkish Fed rate
hike. So, I think people are missing the
bigger story. The bigger story is we are
in a productivity boom showing through
profit margins. We are not hiring human
beings. We're in a point we're in go. We
have a cancer vaccine that comes out.
And as I'm going to show this weekend,
when we say humanity is going to die,
170 million views,
the Matt Schumer article about all jobs,
the Catrini article about no job, about
all jobs being lost,
20, 30, 40 million cancer vaccine, 10.
Nobody wants to hear about the good news
that's coming from AI. They only want to
hear about the bad news. So for all of
you listening playing this stupid game
of the people telling you that the
market's going to crash because AI is
this or this is this or the debt is
coming or all this the market has
discounted all of scenarios they've said
because the PE multiple has gone down
this year while earnings have gone
higher. So I just think people have are
overestimating constantly the
sensitivity that all of these linear
things of the past Smoot Holly oil
interest rates all of this stuff are
going to take down the world and they've
done it repeatedly and it hasn't
happened. What is happening right now is
the most unbelievable technology is
making things better and better for us
every day solving math problems that
have been around since before Einstein.
This is happening regularly and it's
only going to accelerate from here. So,
two things. Um, there was no recession
because not only um is there less
sensitivity to this stuff, but also it's
rigged. If you remember, we had two
quarters of negative GDP growth during
that period. They just said, "Oh, that's
not really a recession cuz we have a
monopoly on being able to call a
recession versus not." Now, the reason I
say that is it was quote unquote so bad
yet they wouldn't acknowledge what was
happening because I actually think that
they understand this. They understand
that the market cannot go down for
prolonged periods of time. And I
continue to say I don't think we're
going to get like an 18-month recession.
I don't think I'll see that again in my
lifetime. And the traditionalists will
get very upset and say what are you
talking about, etc.
Some of it is innovation and
productivity driven. Some of it is just
they have a monetary bazooka that they
are willing to fire at the market
whenever it is needed. The second piece
of this is we are creating jobs in
America. We're just not creating human
jobs. And I think that we've talked
about this in the past where at take our
public company, there are less than 15
humans that work there.
We may have close to 100 digital AI
agent employees. I don't know what the
exact number is, but it is multiples of
the humans
>> to the point where just on one system in
Grockbot, I don't know, I probably have
10 or 15 bots just there myself. And so
you look at that and you say to
yourself,
do the economic measurements need to
change? Do are we going to have to
re-calibrate how we think about the
health of the US economy? Because to
your point, we're looking at outdated
metrics to measure this.
If you keep looking at those metrics
trying to invest in the future, I you're
going to struggle. And I think that's,
you know, your ma your major point here.
It's just like you are going to struggle
to invest using these metrics.
So what should they do? Should they
create new ones? Should they evolve the
definition of these? Like what are you
doing with these metrics? And how are
you thinking about them differently so
that you can invest going forward? Well,
I know that these metrics are wrong for
where we are today. And unfortunately, I
know they're going to get more wrong
going forward. Um, let's just I
very seldom do I remember a month like
this month in my life where all of the
dots come together and it's all related
to AI agents. The Navier Stokes thing
for people, they should understand and
I'm going to put it into um a way that
everyone can can comprehend the
importance of it. So, and this will get
into your point about how statistics
don't fit. And this will end with Eli
Liy. Okay. So, we'll go from Navier
Stokes and I'll end with Eli Liy. I had
no plan for this, but my brain just
popped Eli Liy into my head and said,
"Let's do that." So, Navier Stokes.
Let's go for a ride. Jordy.
>> Yeah. You you you've been around me now
long enough. I can go for a good five
minutes now and give you something you
haven't thought. So let's take Navier
Stokes and rather than go through what
it is and bore people with fluid
dynamics. Let's just view it as it's a
math problem that has existed for a long
time that if you've seen Goodwill
Hunting,
>> you've seen it?
>> Yes.
>> One of my favorite movies. So you
remember um the professor who was
working with Nat Damon, he won the Field
Medal,
>> which is basically like the Nobel Prize
for mathematics. So this is a big deal
these these math problems. So
OpenAI releases that they've solved it.
Now humans get mad. Some say they're
copying it. Whatever. I'll get into that
with Eli Liy. But the main point is
they had 10,000 agents
deal with the problem. Now if you ask me
could this problem have been solved by
humans? I will be the first one to say
absolutely it could have been solved by
humans. The question is not could it
have been solved by humans instead of
AI. The answer is of course it could.
What's the problem? The problem is
if you want the fields metal, you can't
be sharing your information and your
great things. So you just kind of lock
yourself in a box and you try to solve
the problem. You know what that'll
remind people of? The movie Oppenheimer.
You had Grove. You had Oppenheimer.
Groves want he wanted everyone to go
into their own little place. You're
going to work on metals. You're going to
work and then you guys will come
together with your findings. And what
did Oppenheimer say? No, no, no. I want
all of the scientists together. Because
I think if you take a bunch of brains
together and they brainstorm together,
you're going to get to a solution there.
As long as the egos are checked at the
door and you guys are working towards
the same problem. AI agents don't have
human greed. They don't have this. So
they're able to save problems not
through their just their tireless work
and their intelligence, but also through
the collaboration. So 10,000 agents work
together. They're set on different paths
just like Oppenheimer. They come back
with solutions, then they work and they
go to the next one, next one until they
solve the problem. The reason that
eventually leads to Eli Lillian gets
back to your point
that this is the beginning cuz we didn't
have this capability 6 months ago.
>> That is why the hugging face hacking the
human 10 10% chance humanity dies. It's
related to the agents getting so good
that they could break into the internet,
create their own thing, bust the
internet, and everything will dissolve
and you can hack into everything on the
planet. But at the same time, you can
solve a problem that's been around since
before Einstein.
There were 600, I think, Brainiacs as
part of the Manhattan Project. This was
10,000 brainiacs. It'll be a million.
So, what problems can't we solve? That's
why the cancer vaccine, all of this
stuff will end up being a part of it.
And this is why I say to Eli Lily, "So
what does that mean?" Every human
attempt to solve a great problem that
gets up to the 20 yard line. They're in
the red zone. You're putting the red
zone on on on TV and you're like, "Okay,
I'm going to watch the touchdown." These
touchdowns are going to be happening.
The red zone is going to be very busy
because AI agents are going to finish
that last part that five humans, 10
humans, they shared information, but it
wasn't viral. It wasn't everyone on the
planet. So it's not the human beings. If
you stuck 160 IQ people in a room,
10,000 of them, they'd be able to solve
the problem. The problem is we don't
have that. So where Eli Liy figured this
out is they're like that means all of
this dormant IP that exists, all these
biotech companies, they've got something
that people invested in. Let's go
through all of their stuff and see which
public information on their research is
worth something and let's finish it.
Let's let's get a cancer cure. Let's get
something for cholesterol. This is why I
say we're entering a period where the
statistics of what happened that human
beings solve problems that human beings
drove growth it's over. So GDP cannot
like longevity increasing longevity
nobody dying from cancer how does that
impact GDP you have to think really hard
to go through if everyone lives another
75 years healthy what does that mean? So
I'm going to bring it back one more time
and make sure people hear this. This is
the reason why I use the stock market.
There's the reason why when you read
Stan Duck Miller and he says
the best economist in the world stock
market. I believe that too. Rates and
oil are higher. This is bad for the
stock market. The stock market is down
since those two went higher. But you
know what part of it is? It's anything
related to home building, anything
related to consumer staples, anything.
If you go through and you look, and I'll
be showing that this weekend, okay guys,
their earnings are down. The problem is
it doesn't change Micron's earnings. It
doesn't change Google's earnings.
>> AIQ, the uh AI ETF is up, I think I
looked this morning, 25% year-to- date.
>> And that so the problem is oil and rates
are having an impact, but they're having
an impact on the economy that existed
before. So when you're listening to an
economist who went to Harvard and he was
trained really well, he studied history.
Are you going to tell that person that
spent all this money and all this time
and has been told for years how
brilliant they are and all of a sudden
you're going to say, "Hey, everything
you learned is worthless." Of course
not.
>> Well, I've been saying that on the
internet for a long time and they
they're not listening. But yeah,
>> but that's the whole point is that
luckily my father I've said this before.
My father told me at a young age, don't
believe anything you hear from anywhere.
>> Yeah.
>> Adjust your odds on predictions of the
future based on a basian philosophy.
There's new information. The problem is
in my experience having worked with very
smart people the more educated the more
stubborn and less likely to change your
views that has been the number one
biggest negative with cryp for crypto
because for all you crypto fans out
there who controls the world's money the
world's money is controlled for the most
part
>> by the most educated people so why
believe in something that you don't need
to use Michael Sailor's coin Bitcoin
finds you eventually this episode is
brought to you by Lava the Lava card is
the first credit card that allows you to
earn up to 5% back in Bitcoin on every
single purchase. Most cards have steep
annual fees and unclear points programs,
but the Lava card offers a much better
deal. Earn real Bitcoin every time that
you spend. Plus, there's no annual fee.
There's zero FX fees, and zero spread
when you spend internationally. On top
of that, Lava gives you access to a
Bitcoin line of credit, yield on cash,
instant stable coin deposits and
withdrawals, on and off ramps to and
from your bank account, and much, much
more. With Lava, you can borrow against
your Bitcoin at the lowest rates, earn
yield, move money globally, and stack
Bitcoin with each and every purchase you
make. Most financial services squeeze
you with high fees, confusing rewards
programs. Lava keeps it simple, and they
help you build your long-term savings
via your everyday spend. Visit
lava.xyz/pump
to get started in just a few minutes
today. lava.xyz/pom
to get started today.
So, you know who Andrew Yang is?
>> Yes. Right.
>> I saw the you saw where he went on uh on
CNBC.
>> So, there's two components of this. The
first is what you're describing of okay,
we had a couple of smart humans go
together and they try to solve a
problem. Uh the way that I the best
phrase I heard describing the solving of
this hard math problem was brute force.
And I thought that that was like the
perfect example. It's like they just
threw so many quote unquote digital
people with high intelligence at the
problem that in 88 hours they were able
to run through what what 10,000 years of
people trying to solve this, right? And
so just naturally like you eventually
figure it out. Um
then the open AI hugging face incident
is the negative side of this. Mhm.
>> And I think every single smart person I
know has not really talked that much
about this publicly because in private
what they're all saying. There's more to
this story and I don't know what that is
and so I don't want to have egg on my
face when I come out and talk about it.
>> Mhm.
>> We got a breadcrumb this week on CNBC.
I have no clue if this is true.
>> Right.
>> But Andrew Yang, who I would actually
put him I listened to a a speech he gave
in Philadelphia. Um, this is maybe
almost 10 years ago and he was very pro
technology. He was very much like, "Hey,
I want to be the president of the United
States and I I'm going to embrace
technology." I probably disagree with a
lot of his ideas, but I I like the fact
that he's pro technology. He claims that
he talked to a lab leader. So, somebody
who was in a leadership position at one
of the labs, and they claim, and I think
the exact thing that he talked about was
self-replicating code, and they littered
the internet. And then he went as far as
to say the reason why Antropic and Open
AI are saying, "Whoa, slow down is
because these agents basically can
respawn themselves and do this exact
same thing over and over again because
they have polluted the internet. And now
in order for them to train models, they
he claims anthropic and open AAI believe
they have to build a synthetic internet
to now train on it."
>> I'm just going to call it what I think
it is. This sounds batshit crazy, but
given the times we're living in, it's
not a 0% probability. Like, I don't
know, maybe it's a 20% probability
that's what happened. How do you, as an
investor, somebody who's building with
this using this technology? How do you
navigate a story that scares a lot of
people? They know they don't know
everything. And then you get some crazy
detail like that said publicly by
somebody who I think most people are
like, "All right, he's not incentivized
to like, you know, lie or or or make it
up.
This is called living life."
I I mean, I I hate to say this, but do
you think you know everything that's
happened that we were this close to
extinction of the planet over the last
whatever? Do you think if they knew that
an asteroid was coming to the earth and
was going to hit here in 50 years that
they'd be publicly saying that this
tells us everything?
>> Of course. So here here here's the
reality of the situation. Um
>> do I believe that we haven't seen
everything? Yes. Do I believe that the
pause is related to the security risk,
meaning the progress getting ahead of
the safety? 100%. Do I also believe that
Andrew Yang has a political reason to
say what he said? Yes, 100%. Do I think
it's possible that one of the labs that
said it to Andrew Yang is also a
political like are you calling it a
maybe I think in history we've called
them influence operations or a scop from
the labs and we have found a useful uh
person who will go and repeat what they
told him
>> I naturally don't trust
>> okay
>> any human
>> man you are so politically correct um
>> live a little Jordy
>> no I but I I just think in a world where
people's incentives have always tended
to lead with themselves, um I I just
>> I don't disagree that there's a very
high odds that he was fed information
that would uh enhance the lab's uh uh
initiatives.
>> Yeah. I So I think the main point to
people is um we don't know every right
now. If I had to guess, since 9/11,
how many terror plots do you think were
stopped by the United States government
that were significant?
Hundreds
>> easily. Okay. So, I don't see it as any
different. Yes, I believe AI is a
dangerous thing, but I also believe
bioteterrorism is dangerous and missiles
are dangerous and nuclear is dangerous
and all these things are dangerous and
there are humans that want to do things.
And what I'm hopeful is that by them
finding this and already coming up with
what the next solution would be, that's
the way you figure out how to continue
to grow. I think the pause that will
happen, which is why when I got an
outreach on, and this happens because I
talked to so many hedge fund people, the
outreach on Sunday of this week before
the futures opened up. Two funny parts
about this. One is people calling me up
going, "I know what you're going to say,
but
is this an overreaction?"
Yes, this is an overreaction. This will
not stop compute. If anything, it'll
probably accelerate compute. So, that
was the first one. The second one was,
"How far down do you think the S&P will
be when it opens?" And my answer was,
"Why don't you go to Coinbase and look
at the spy per?" And so, I like doing
this stuff now to people because I'm
like, "You realize the markets trade
247, guys. You can go look at anything
you want. You better start paying
attention to why Stan Ducken Miller
bought into Hyperlid and start
understanding what a purpose. Um, so I
do think that this stuff goes on. I do
think that people have to realize that
part of the reason that the S&P multiple
has contracted and I've talked about it
before. I am not bullish on the growth
in public equities as an investment by
the time we get to 2030. The reason for
that is what I read in situational
awareness and we are exactly on pace if
not 6 months ahead in Leopold's article.
You should all pull it up and one day
when you have a couple hours ask for the
timeline. I'll be showing it on the
video but societal
impacts are happening. Governments are
being polarized. We've got one party
that wants to stop data centers. Like
this is all part of the forecast that
would happen. The part that we start to
get into is that all companies will be
disrupted. Hackings will happen. Which
is the main reason why for me what
people have to start understanding and I
will be spending a lot of time with the
wealthiest institutions on the planet.
This week I start my crypto focus
research video every single week. But it
is going to be making people understand
why I have 46 names in the index, what
it represents, what ghost rails are,
what this whole situation is. Because
the blockchain is one of the solutions
to the problem we're talking about.
Agents will be transacting with each
other. The blockchain is necessary. Like
everything about what is bad for agent
swarms reaching this point is fantastic
for crypto. Which is why at the end of
the day for all of you thinking this is
going to happen because of liquidity.
No, this is not about liquidity. This is
about dormant liquidity that's been
locked up forever in this fiat Ponzi
scheme finally being able to be used to
buy coffee and agents will be the one
doing it where friction of time finally
comes in because humans wanted to keep
things at these long settlements because
the middlemen make vigs on it. Well,
this isn't going to happen when agents
are making decisions. And I'll finish it
with this. I had a story said to me
which I didn't know was true. Maybe
you've heard this.
This person said to me that they went to
go buy a ticket for an airline on Delta.
Okay. And
they went at say 2:00 in the afternoon.
They didn't buy it. They came back later
in the day and the price was
significantly higher. And then they came
back again and it was higher again. And
they interpreted this that it was a
personalized price movement that they
understood and it sounded very agentic
to me. So I had no idea. Have you heard
this?
>> No.
>> So if you go just type in has this been
happening? Is this a complaint that's
happened from customers that AI agents
are trying to get the best price on
things?
I don't know. They haven't admitted
anything. So for Delta, I'm not saying
this is true, but if you go on the
internet or you just going to an LLM and
you ask, this has gotten to the
government complaint side and it has
been something there. And it makes sense
to me because
>> what exactly are the agents doing?
>> The agents are driving the price higher
thinking that the person they're trying
to personalize the ability of the person
to pay.
>> So this is a way for companies to make
more money. It's kind of like if you go
I mean StubHub. They're using AI.
They're using AI to try to predict how
much do I think Jordy will pay for this
flight
>> relative to another person.
>> At the same time, now the consumers are
armed with AI agents who are basically
what are all the angles to get Delta to
give me a cheaper price.
>> And that's the way
>> agent on agent warfare
>> and that's what normalizes everything
because in the end the agents that are
controlling the wallets win. The company
agents do not win because they only have
one thing to do. This agent can go to a
billion other airlines, go through a
billion other channels and more
importantly can be anonymous. This is
why privacy businessto business. So when
you hear about Zcash and you hear about
Near and you hear about these things and
you go why are these things leading like
these are the things leading right now
in September and you could say well this
is DeFi cash this is that no to me this
is the rise of agents and privacy
they're they're needed because
businessto business in this Delta
example meaning Jord's business wants to
go buy a ticket he doesn't want them to
know who they are and where he's
normally sits and all this so the agent
is anonymous and they're just dealing in
this transaction and moving around. You
can do that when you can go through it.
This is why if you guys haven't seen it
yet, have you seen the company Instinct
AI?
>> Yeah, I use it.
>> You do?
>> Yeah.
>> Do you like it?
>> Yeah, I like it a lot.
>> Okay. So, if you guys haven't seen this,
we're in the personal assistant world.
So, this is what agents are going to do.
Now, I'm sure you haven't used it with
wallet. Have you used it with wallet
stuff yet?
>> No.
>> Okay. But you use it for like other
things, not just email, but like if
you're going to go travel to another
country and you need to get a visa and
get your documents out, it'll do all
your documents for you.
>> I'll give you a perfect example what I
used it for. I had a breakfast scheduled
for Thursday at 7:00 a.m. 7 a.m. guy.
And uh it was with uh two very important
people. And um I had it go and make the
reservation. Three very important
>> send the uh calendar invite. Well, I'll
tell you a funny thing that one of these
important people did. I actually think
you know one of them. Um, and uh, then
they emailed me the next day and said,
"Hey, by the way, we need to move it to
Friday." So, usually that would be a
pain. You got to go, you got to move the
calendar invite, then you got to go
cancel one reservation. You got to do
and so I was just like, could it do it?
I didn't give it credentials. Any of
this stuff, right? And I just said, move
the reservation to Friday. And it
instinctively knew move the calendar
invite, cancel Thursday, make
reservation for Friday.
>> And it didn't. It came back in like 2
minutes. And I said to myself, that was
awesome. Now, uh, as you know, when uh
you go to breakfast with two very
important people, this one genius today
wanted to fight me over who was going to
pay. And he I'm going to give alpha to
everyone right now. He turned to the
waitress and said, "He can't pay. It's
his birthday.
And of course, she was like, "Oh, I
can't let you pay." And so now I feel
like I'm armed with a new uh a new
little trick is if you ever get in a in
a who's going to pay battle, just drop
that one real quick and you'll win. Um
but this whole instinct thing was it was
incredibly impressive. And so now I've
started to kind of put like what else
could it do? And there's been a couple
other things like that where I've been
like, "Okay, we're we're in a different
regime now."
>> Have you seen the valuation of the
company now? They're trying to raise
that. I I don't want to uh to brag, but
um there is a uh upand cominging very
good young investor who um I invested in
his fund.
>> Mhm.
>> To support him, but also I thought he
could do a good job. And uh he's been
talking about things are going well, but
he hasn't really been talking. And he
recently sent an update. He said, "Fine,
I'll tell you guys." He was one of the
early investors in Instinct. And so my
exposure is like minuscule compared to
anyone who invested directly. But I said
to him, I said, "That one decision is
probably going to make his career." I
mean, this thing went from founded to 10
billion in a year.
>> A year,
>> year and a half, something like that.
>> If you look at like a month ago, the
rumors were valuation of 2.5 billion.
Now, the valuation is 10. Correct.
>> So, again, I I let the market speak to
me about what's happening. Instinct is
critical to crypto.
One of my favorite Peter Teal lessons,
the more steep the valuation climb,
the more likely the company's
undervalued.
>> Mhm.
>> And so when people see something go from
500 million to 2.5 billion to 10 billion
in less than 3 months,
>> the average person would say, "It's
overvalued. This is insane. Why are
people doing that?" one of the best
venture investors in the world claims
when you see that that actually means
that 10 billion would be underval like
that there's way more runway there's
something that the market knows
>> that people don't which I think lines up
directly with you saying like hello guys
this is a way bigger market these are
way more important technologies and
products than people are giving you know
uh uh kind of credit to at the moment
>> yeah and here here's the issue and this
fits into anthropic and open AI why is
everyone scared about the AI bubble why
are scared of it. Well, because
Anthropic and OpenAI are basically the
AI bubble. Like they're going to control
as much as 50% of compute a year from
now.
>> You think so?
>> That's what all the story somewhere
between a third and 50%. Brad Gersonner
just talked about it on the all-in pod
on his presentation at the summit. Uh so
you can go look at the deck. I mean,
we're talking about them controlling 50%
of compute. Compute is the entire S&P
500 right now as far as I'm concerned.
like it's all about compute. So two
companies, they're not even public. They
don't release their numbers. Instinct,
>> no, they have 80% margins before COGS.
>> Instinct, I'm sure if you go look, how
much money have you paid Instinct?
>> Zero.
>> So, but they're worth 10 billion.
>> Meta is a personal assistant company.
>> Yeah. Have you used Muse yet?
>> I haven't used Muse yet.
>> So, I recently signed up. I I am uh
doing a little experiment and I'm going
to kind of come out and say, "Okay, I've
used Grock. I've got Instinct. I'm going
to use Muse. There's a lot of overlap in
what they can do, but I do think the
interfaces, the setup, the way that they
present the products, like there's some
significant differences. Um,
I actually think that we're going to end
up using multiple ones, but it is
fascinating to me because
the common layer among all of this is
the context, the memory. And it feels
like people are now mentally wrapping
their head around I am long the idea of
personal assistance or Sylvia or you
know chatbt or claude or whatever. So
like the interface and the compute
component or the model I think people
are like duh this is going to be
valuable. I am shocked at how little
attention the memory layer is getting.
And memory not just being in the sense
of memory for me as an individual and I
want to be able to use Instinct or Grock
or Muse,
>> but when a new one comes out, we were
just talking with uh with some of the
folks here, you know, Matt, our video
editor, and uh Isaac were talking about
when a new one comes out, they almost
feel like I don't want to go sign up for
it because in two weeks there's going to
be a new one. And how do you keep doing
that? Well, if you have one shared
memory, you can almost use these as
databases. Now, that reminds me, did I
don't know if you follow Signal, S I G N
U L L on uh on X.
Very good uh follow very thoughtful
anonymous account. Um and
I think it's a guy he he was talking
about this idea of he doesn't actually
go into the apps anymore. So, he was
talking about his email. he interfaces
with his email via the agent. And so he
was like, "My email has just become a
database. It's just a, you know, a
record uh tracker. I do my email in the
agent interface of chat or whatever."
And so why do I need to go into Gmail if
that's where the world's headed? Nobody
is ready. So let let me ask you one
question then I'm going to I'm going to
direct this towards the most important
thing I will say to people on this and
possibly ever in this bridging of of the
current world the agentic side in
crypto. So in your example of the
restaurant
>> Mhm.
>> you could have done that yourself right
>> maybe.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> I'm not too smart but yeah
>> you could have asked someone else
whatever. But if you did it yourself
what did you save? You didn't save any
money. What'd you save?
>> Time. Yeah.
>> Okay. So, this is the thing I want to I
want to bring back to people. When you
gave me the discussion about Matt and
Isaac and they can't keep up with AI,
that means we've reached a point of
effectively recursive self-improvement,
meaning the models are being released
faster than we can comprehend how to go
through. That's all that means. Like,
they're coming out too fast. It's not
that we don't have the capabilities.
it it's going too fast.
>> There's one nuance which is um models.
Yes. I actually think that
if we just look over the last six
months, we got clawed updates, we got a
lot of Chinese open source, we got
Astra, like like there have been a
number of models.
I think that there's almost this
blending though of like model and
product now. like Muse is not
necessarily the model, but Muse is
wrapped around a model and
>> Astra comes out and now people are
almost interchangeably thinking about
like I could use Astra or I could use
Muse.
>> And so like maybe I would just say it's
just the assault of options
>> and and they're going to show up in so
many different ways and formats and it's
like you basically gave this brand new
technology to really smart
entrepreneurial people and they're going
to figure out every way to cut, slice
it, etc. to go after
>> users and the users are on the other end
like oh my god I'm under attack. So, the
app store for everyone on their phone,
like I don't know how many pages you
have on your iPhone, but you have a lot
because you're like, "Oh, this would be
a great app to add." When they first
came out, I'll just use the GPS or the
the driving as there. I remember the
first time someone told me about Ways
and I was like, "Oh my god, it's got
traffic and police. This is great. Okay,
it took a while for Google Maps to catch
up to Ways." And so I used ways for
let's say a year or two or maybe even
three before I've switched over to
Google Maps. Now Ways comes out and then
there's 1,700 of them the next day. They
come out faster. So if you use the best
one, it's going to be enormous.
Again, I'm going to take it back to the
exact same thing in Leopold's
figure 70 or page 71. At some point
we're moving so fast in terms of change
that human beings can't keep up with it.
And what do we need at that point? We
need the agents. The agents are
necessary to do the stuff for us. So
eventually like you have with your chief
of staff in Grock, you will have a chief
of staff where you say, "Hey, I want you
to go build this stuff for me today."
And it'll decide whether to use Astra or
Claude or Google Maps or Ways. That's
what's going to happen. The reason this
is important is for all the crypto
innovators, this has followed the same
playbook as the internet. The exact same
one. The internet comes out in 1994.
We have the.com bubble until 2008. So
basically 14 years after, let's just say
the original white paper Netscape as
opposed to the Bitcoin white paper. You
have people doubting it. The way I said,
yeah, I was around some people and had
dinner and they're like they're done
with Bitcoin. like they don't believe in
it anymore. And I was like, "Wow, just
as I'm saying, this is the beginning of
the biggest move ever."
But I'm glad you don't see it because
you don't believe in the other stuff.
And this is where I'm a Bitcoin maxi in
the very long term. Woo! No, no, no. I
believe if you want to, let's let me
rephrase it. I want an asset that will
be growing in value for the next 30
years, the only one I can say in my
brain with certainty for the next 30
years. Not the next five, not the next
three that I believe is Bitcoin. That's
it. The rest are innovations. They're
like that story you gave of how many
apps. It's like the LLMs. They just go
faster and the competition comes. And
growth has something to do with not just
an innovative idea, but will competition
catch up? And I think competition
catches up. So the growth trajectory,
the terminal value, as we talked about
is gone. So I have written a paper about
ghost rails, which is when you go to
China and you see all these buildings
that are built, they were built for a
reason. They were built by the Chinese
believing that they'd be flooded with
people and the second that the people
moved in, they'd start building
restaurants and they'd start and every
the ecosystem would just light up. These
are the ghost cities in China.
>> The ghost cities in China. That's where
crypto is right now. They're ghost
rails. They're not being used because
humans would never use them for the
reasons that you guys are talking about.
We're not capable or needing something
so fast that's fractionalized. We don't
need it. Bitcoin. You need something
like Bitcoin to bring the
entrepreneurial capital in. That's what
the internet was. Ethereum and Bitcoin
represent the internet. You don't know
what it means. You don't know how to
value it. But it is the thing that will
have all of these layer 2 built on top
of it, which is what happens when you
light up the city. The reason we are
lighting up the city now, people, is
because the users of those rails are
finally coming in. And they're instinct
AI, their muse, and they're all the ones
that are coming. That's why the swarm
swarm equals cryptog guardrails. Plain
and simple for me. And again, this is a
macro person saying, "I've seen this act
before. The railroads, we build all
these railroads. There's tons of debt."
Yeah. Because we're betting when the
humans are going to use them relative to
the debt maturing. This is not the same
story. We are not building AI hoping
that humans will come in and use it. We
solved that problem in October of last
year. The agents were the ones who were
going to use the compute. They're the
ones sucking up the tokens and right now
they're about to suck up transactions
and payments because consumer agents
will be the story for the next year.
>> Today's episode is brought to you by
Arch Public. Arch Public has just
expanded its agentic trading platform
beyond crypto. So pay attention. This is
a big one. Now they are automating
strategies across stocks, commodities,
and ETFs. And I think that this is going
to be huge. You can now automatically
take profits when one market hits new
all-time highs and rotate that capital
into other markets showing more
opportunity. Whether you're rotating
capital into AI stocks, gold, if you're
investing in the S&P 500, or you're
accumulating Bitcoin, Arch Public brings
real discipline and automation to your
investment strategy. Additionally,
they've launched a powerful new tax loss
harvesting tool. With crypto being so
volatile and its exemption from the wash
sale rule, Arch Public can offset gains
with losses without compromising your
long-term positions. It's exactly what
every serious investor does.
Institutional grade automation that
works across every major asset class.
There's no more emotional trading, no
more missing tax opportunities, just
smarter, hands-free execution of your
preferred strategies. Go to
archpubic.com
right now. Connect with our team, set up
a time, bring your accountant if you'd
like. Then you can learn what automated
trading can do for you. archpub.com.
Today's episode is brought to you by
Token 2049. The largest conference in
crypto is back. Token 2049 will host
25,000 people, 300 speakers, and a
thousand plus side events in Singapore
on October 7th and 8th at Marina Bay
Sands. The speaker list is absolutely
stacked. Shane Copeland from Poly
Market, Jeff Yan from Hyperlquid, Adena
Freriedman from NASDAQ, Arthur Hayes,
Balagi, and Eric Trump. Crypto and
traditional finance in the same
building, which tells you a lot about
where this is going. And the conference
runs right into F1 weekend, so the whole
thing turns into one giant week. If
you're headed to Singapore, use code
POMP 10 for 10% off your ticket. Token
2049, October 7th and 8th in Singapore.
Go check them out in the link in the
description. So, I know that you're very
bullish on uh non Bitcoin crypto stuff.
And as you know, uh I'm less bullish on
that stuff. Uh and some of it admittedly
may just be uh I historically have seen
lots of promises, not a lot of results,
and these things go up, they go down,
you can trade it, right? But for the
most part, everything ends up at
>> Pets.com. Pets.com.
>> Yeah. You just people uh they can go out
into the wilderness, but they want to
come home and home is Bitcoin is
basically the the uh the story of the
crypto industry for a long time. Now,
with that said, if I try to be as
intellectually honest as possible and I
flip around the table and argue against
that view, pretty much the only thing
that I could wrap my head around where
I'm like, okay, this would be my best
argument is you have a expanding market
of users, not from humans, but from the
agents. So if you go back to, you know,
our company of 15 or less people and
tens of maybe 100 plus agents, that's a
pretty big expansion without the humans
needing to grow very quickly. So if that
is the case, then they do need somewhere
to go. Now the question or or maybe the
thing I don't know is do they just use
stable coins and Bitcoin or do they go
to what you call like these ghost rails?
If they go longtail into the ghost
rails, etc., then yes, you'll have a lot
more usage. you'll have a lot more
adoption and just naturally you have
assets that will go up in in price.
One detail that does not get a lot of
attention which I think is hiding in
plain sight. You know who one of the the
most gung-ho kind of supportive people
of AI investing hundreds of millions of
dollars in AI and no one ever talks
about them? Tether.
Why is Tether investing so much money in
AI?
My belief is because Paulo
understands exactly what's happening and
if you can create
models, privacy agents, stable coins,
that becomes a stack that's really
powerful. You know who else seems to be
very interested in AI in crypto? Vlad.
Vlad. But Stripe, I don't know if you
saw the recent chart of Tempo,
>> and all my friends over at Tempo will be
excited that I'm bringing them up, but
the chart is incredibly impressive. It's
ramping.
>> Mhm.
>> Now, what are they doing in terms of is
Stripe somehow pushing it and giving it
an advantage? Is there some sort of like
seeding? You know, I always go back to
when Figure Technologies first started,
Mike wanted to create a decentralized
DTCC or clearing house and nobody was
there. it was a ghost settlement. So
he's like, "Well, I'll get in the
origination business to kind of get one
side of the marketplace going and then
I'll go and get the other side and and
induce them essentially."
>> Mhm.
>> If that's what's happening, okay, we we
should probably understand that. But
even if that's happening, adoption is
ramping. And so you have some of the
largest financial players in the world
who all seem to be arriving at crypto
and AI is merging here. And I think
you're probably from the investment side
one of the only people in the world
raising your hand saying guys this
convergence is where majority of the
asymmetry is going to be for the next 5
or 10 years.
>> So let let me take you down why this has
been so interesting to me. I don't think
I would have made this bet on AI and
crypto merging which is the bet I made 2
years ago without having gone to
Singularity University in 2013. I've
talked about the story but I came back
from China and the ghost city thing was
now a past. It was basically they're
done. They're not going to be driving
global growth anymore. The one of the
funniest things about to get back to the
oil thing. So, one of my first trips to
to China or maybe my third or fourth,
oil was at 150. That was back in 2008. I
I I want to say that again.
In 2008, the price of oil was
150.
Where is it today? It's 100.
Household net worth is up I think three
and a half times. It's at 195 trillion.
Not the assets, the net worth.
So I recognize that this was now stupid.
We had printed money to a an enormous
potential. The oil price relative to
disposable income is the lowest ever in
the history of the country. Yet oil
matters to all of us. We're going to die
with oil. It's going to kill the
economy. Do you think one person who's
worth three and a half times what they
were worth when that's the total sum is
three and a half times what it was when
oil was 150. So now oil's at a discount.
So relative to the household net worth.
This is literally stupid. People try to
scare you and they try to go through it.
I went to Silicon Valley cuz I had to
ask the question. I know the S&P 500 is
about innovation. That's what it is.
It's an innovation index. It's about
things will be better. It's the Joseph
Shumper we go through. It's the actual
definition of we get rid of the weak, we
keep the new, but it's about creative
destruction. The mag seven get to be
concentrated anthropic and open AI
duopoly. It's about creative
destruction. So for me as a macro
person, I think I'm the only one my age
that had the curiosity to go, if not
commodities, if not housing, if not
this, then what? What is this Amazon
thing traded in infinity PE for the last
17 years up 26,000? I'm curious. I
wanted to go see and I went in there and
heard that I wasn't going to die. And
I'm looking around going, "What? They're
not talking about this on on TV. They're
saying we're all going to die tomorrow.
I'm being told by you guys that we'll
figure out how to live forever." And if
that's the case, I need to change my
macro mind and start thinking about what
that means. And I didn't buy into
Bitcoin at that point, but I did buy
into by 2014 and 15 into the blockchain.
It made sense to me that this is where
business would be conducted. Now, fast
forward a decade. It's playing the exact
same path as the internet. And that's
the one thing I will say to people. It
took a long time. Netscape was 94. The
iPhone was 2007. It was 13 years. The
App Store came later. So, let's say
2009.
15 years. When did the Bitcoin white
paper came out? Where are we now? We're
on the exact same timeline. You need to
have the users come in for the benefit
of what happens. If there is no
smartphone, there is no Uber. You can't
carry your laptop around and start
ordering. You needed this smartphone
thing. And right now, the AI agents are
there. So, when I listen to one of the
former or one of the co-authors of the
Transformer paper, which opened up AI,
and I'm listening to him inside the
crypto space in Near doing this agent to
agent, and I look at Near and I see it
going parabolic the same time that Zcash
is in the same time Instinct is coming
out. I'm like, whoa, agents are
happening. So, I'm a macro person that
does not believe he's smart. What I
believe is I let the market and the
capital going as insider information for
what's happening. That's why Bitcoin is
not the right place to look. And for all
of you who think,
>> if you think that Bitcoin was going to
get to 20 trillion
without the wealthy old baby boomers to
believe in it, you're crazy. waiting for
everyone to die to hand their money down
the kids is not a short-term what I'm
talking about you actually need the
innovation to be useful and as much as I
love Bitcoin as collateral and as large
transactions and the trust Ethereum
trust these are the places that because
of their size and their legacy they will
be the main ones that will make all of
the institutions comfortable you need an
innovation to get the entrepreneurs to
build on it and keep going and that's
where the ghost city comes in for that
you need agents and the agents are
coming Okay, let me play uh Devil's
Advocate.
>> Okay,
>> the ghost cities are still empty in
China.
>> No, they're not.
>> The rails are still empty today.
At what point do you say
we've gone long enough, I have to change
my mind? Is this like a over the next
year, over the next 5 years, like how do
you look at we know the technology is
there.
What is like your exit point from this
view of either level of adoption
timeline like how do you think about
okay you know I I believe this is going
to happen at what point would you change
your mind if it doesn't
>> so I'm going to use the Micron example
last year the or over the year the
reason I made so much money in micron
flex is because of inference I was
betting on what is basically agents
>> we didn't have we had to get the IQ up
to 150 before the agents would kick in
that's I'm saying if you look at the
Leopold that he laid it all out. The one
thing I know about the singularity is
it's a math problem.
>> Mhm.
>> And I know this is going to sound
strange to people, but it's a math
problem. It really is. Like it's just a
you're compounding at a certain rate.
That's why when they say we're going to
eventually run into where it's not going
to compound anymore. Moore's law will
end. Well, we got past that and we went
to the next thing and the next thing and
the next thing. It's a math problem. So
that means that a year from now, agents
will be proliferating. There's no way
they won't be unless they destroy the
internet and all humanity.
>> Do you know why I think that this is
like a foregone conclusion? I had a
realization this week that I am uh sad
to admit, but it's true. I I've come to
terms with it.
>> Okay.
>> The agents are smarter than me.
>> The like IQ wise, there are now agents
that are
>> just now at 150. You didn't think maybe
110, 120. Well, 80 IQ, you know, there
was it wasn't a high bar they had to
jump over. But like it it hit me. I'm
like, "Wait a minute. The agent is
actually smarter than me now,
>> right?" And so once you hit a 150, I
mean, there's very few people in the
world that is not smarter than, right?
There is, however, a 13-year-old kid
here in I believe he's in New York who
recently um he's at NYU and uh he got
like a 1590 on the SAT at 10 years old
or something, right? He's got like 160
IQ. So like there there's a couple out
there. Um not me. they're not smarter
than 150 IQ LLM.
So you you look at that and you say okay
wait a second if we all are comfortable
admitting to ourselves that they are
smarter than us now then it is just a
context and memory problem right it's
just like how much context do they have
and can they persistently hold that
memory and then in a weird way of like
can you prompt it correctly
>> but like the horsepower is there and so
if that is all true of course they're
going to become pervasive everywhere
because people for centuries have been
looking for the highest IQ most
intelligence they could possibly find.
>> So, let's go back to your question for
everyone listening.
If Bitcoin is below 80,000, okay, I'll
even say by the end of October, there's
a problem. And so, I'm going to use the
Micron example.
The reason Micron went higher is because
you go from very few people believing or
seeing the economic impact from the
thing. So, inference was becoming
something. And for those of you who are
subscribers, if you go to the piece I
wrote in May about inference and I
highlight the Sundar Pachai, how many
trillions of tokens were used and I go
into every earnings report, like 20 of
them about the inference explosion. You
have no excuses as an investor to not
have bought Micron at 110. Now, I didn't
see institutions
jumping on board until October of last
year. M
>> so we're talking about from May to
October the price is going up it's above
200 and blah blah blah
>> it takes time to do research investment
>> it takes time for people to see the
fundamentals so the reason I said
October
I'm watching Zcash and near because they
represent the true the people that are
like oh my god the agentic stuff is
picking up every day what you said about
tempo Robin Hood chain like Robin Hood
chain was mainly meme stuff I don't care
about meme activity but you have meme
activity before everyone else gets on
board, before the agents start
transacting. People don't trust the
agents, they don't want to go through,
but the technology is happening and
instinct and meta are a representation.
Remember the meta situation? The most
important thing to look at is back in
June, what did Zuckerberg say? He said
he's been disappointed in the progress
in AI. If you go back and look, and I
don't know if you remember it, he
literally said in a town hall meeting
inside the walls that got leaked, he was
disappointed. Here we are now 3 months
later. They're releasing Muse Personal
Assistant. Maybe they're releasing it
because Instinct is gathering so much
steam and Meta's stock was trading near
52- week lows. Now it's back above the
200 day moving average. I think the
Agentic side is kicking into this and
there's more than that happening. If I
go look at all of the Agentic type
trades, well, the MAG 7 benefit from
agents in a much bigger way.
Salesforce.com benefits in agents. What
else benefits from agents? Cybertocks.
Like this is a new index I'm putting
together. It's like if you believe
agents are here, well then cyber is
worth more because they can disrupt
anything. If you believe agents are
here, then Salesforce actually does have
usefulness at this point because the
agents are here and people haven't moved
off of Salesforce.com and that's not
going to happen for the Fortune 500
companies. So they should see an
inflection in terms of getting revenues
in the door. So for everything in the
market, I'm already seeing the agentics
state play out. Bitcoin to me is a
summation of the entire ecosystem and
agents if they're driving it, we should
see the price go higher. When we get
above 82,000, as I said before, there is
so much volume that happened there.
That's the point in time when I think
people gave up the last time when the
fall happened after October 10th.
Everyone picked a point like, okay, we
can buy it now. It's going back. Stocks
went higher and what happened? Crypto
fell lower again. It broke away from
stocks. And why was that? As you and I
talked about, South Korea didn't care
about crypto anymore. They cared about
AI. AI is not the same trade anymore.
It's not as easy. And the agentic side
isn't as good as the infrastructure
trade. So Micron gave me the belief that
if you're going to get into it, you have
to get into it one when it's very very
early, which is what it is in agents.
Number two, once it starts breaking
above key levels, it should not look
back. We haven't done that yet in in
Bitcoin and the ecosystem, but the
ecosystem 46 name basket I have is up
big for the year and most of it's being
driven by the AI agent side.
>> I have good news for you. I just
>> I love good news.
>> I just looked at what you were talking
we don't have to wait till the end of
October. Bitcoin is back over $80,000
right now.
>> Okay. So
>> So it's got to stay right.
>> What time is it?
>> 11:00 on
>> that took uh 27 minutes for your
prediction to be right. Um all right,
before we go uh this is a very big week
for you. Um you are launching the crypto
version of the research. Um can you tell
us what exactly are you launching and
then where can people go subscribe check
it out learn uh learn about it?
>> Yeah. So for those of you who watch the
video first of all that I do every
Sunday morning on Sunday morning this is
going to be in the same form.
>> Okay. The reason I've kept everything
the same is the feedback I've gotten
from people both very sophisticated
macro people and then retail people is I
make it easy enough in terms of the the
approach and the usage of the slides to
get people to consume the information. I
believe that I educate people and they
get more comfortable. I'm going to do
the exact same thing with crypto which
is something that even retail people in
crypto I don't think understand enough
yet. how it all connects. What we talked
about here today with agents, this is a
very nuanced thing. I think outside of
the people we mentioned, which are the
people running that are actually
quantitative tech people, I'm trying to
turn this into everyday life, like a
restaurant. Okay, Instinct AI, you guys
should go look at it. And more
importantly, that will have a wallet
attached to it where the maximum is $100
and you can't get into trouble if you
have $100. It has a maximum because it's
programmable. You can't do more than
this. So, I want you to go order this,
buy this, go to Uber, do this, and then
you refill it and you go through it the
same way you would like a Dunkin Donuts
card where maximum is there and you have
to put more money in. Well, if during
the week you're having your assistant,
hey, hey, I'm not going to be back home
in time. Go to Door Dash, get me some
food, whatever I like, blah blah blah,
and then you move on, it's your personal
assistant and it's going to have access
to Amazon and all of those things. So,
for me to show people the news that's
happening each week, I mentioned Zcash,
I mentioned Near. I'm sure 95 to 99% of
people listening to this don't know what
those two things are, especially the
traditional finance world. So, this is
going to be an education. It's going to
start with the first video saying why
now in crypto. This is to get people
excited about why I'm so emphatic about
this being the turnover point for AI,
but then each week from that point, it's
going to go through the verticals. I
have 10 verticals so they can start to
understand why tokenization is so
important. We didn't even get into it,
but if you ask me what's more important
than stable coins, tokenizing things is
the most important step we're taking in
this entire crypto place.
>> And and the regulators now have just
made a huge announcement. They're
allowing this stuff to happen
>> for 5 years. They're exemp I mean 5
years. This is a big deal. That's why
the Clarity Act doesn't matter. That's
why people have to understand that this
is going to happen because it's global.
And by them exempting things for a
period of time and allowing this to
happen tokenize tokenizing everything
over time unleashes so much dormant
liquidity. So M2 guys you've learned
this old economic book. We have enough
assets in this levered world that are
sitting there doing nothing. And if you
can release them and say, "Hey, I want
to borrow money in my business. I've got
my house. It's the only thing I have in
value. I don't have any cash. I don't
want to go to the bat and can borrow
money. How about this? I give you a
programmable token. You take a piece of
my house, this is what it's valued at,
and then I own it back the next day
because I posted as collateral, we did
something, and because I'm only doing it
for one day, everything happens
instantaneously. So, the friction in
business really slows down you buy a
house. So, I'm going to try to educate
people. I think it is the single most
important thing from an investment
standpoint. And if you've listened to me
long enough and think that I have a
different view than most people, I do
believe your stocks that are
underperforming this year relative to
earnings is going to be a major story.
If you own bonds, they're unchanged over
the last seven, eight years. You've got
nothing from bonds if you're stuck in
private credit. You're going to be going
through pain getting your money back.
This is the fiat system getting old and
dying. That's what it is. Entrepreneurs
are going to win, but there's no way to
invest in the non-public stocks other
than crypto. Crypto is a representation
of the entrepreneurs of the future using
the financial guardrails because they're
going to be all AI native. And what are
we saying? Agents are going to use the
guardrails. This system is being built
through a backdoor and I'm going to try
to make sure people understand it.
>> Where can we send people?
>> Uh they can always go to viser-labs.com
and it'll send you back. But
ai22vresearch.com
you can go see it there. Everything will
be up on the site. I'm going to release
a video and a paper this week. The paper
will be on ghost rails. It will bring
Mark Andre in who told us all in 2014
that this moment was coming. We think it
was Bitcoin. But in the paper he says
Bitcoin but what has happened is the
ecosystem has grown into more than
Bitcoin. It has grown into this whole
thing of micro payments and everything
else. That's why you need to read it and
that's why you'll go through it.
>> I play devil's advocate with you today.
But you want to know how we would agree
>> how
>> I am pretty sure that
Sylvia in the public markets is the only
publicly traded company that is merging
AI and Bitcoin together.
So I completely agree with everything
you're saying. And it's been fun to uh
antagonize you and get you to explain
it. See you guys next time.